<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>programming on Bergercookie's Thoughtstream</title><link>https://bergercookie.dev/categories/programming/</link><description>Recent content in programming on Bergercookie's Thoughtstream</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://bergercookie.dev/categories/programming/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>5 Albert Plugins to 5 Workflow Issues</title><link>https://bergercookie.dev/post/5-albert-plugins-to-5-common-problems/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bergercookie.dev/post/5-albert-plugins-to-5-common-problems/</guid><description>This is part two of my articles on the Albert launcher. Read the first part here
This post outlines 5 common issues that I had been facing during my day-to-day development and the solutions that I came up with via 5 Albert plugins respectively.
TL;DR The purpose of these plugins is a) to avoid context-switching and b) have a single tool with a single interface instead X different tools with their own corresponding interfaces.</description></item><item><title>Scratchpad - Create multi-ISO USBs with Easy2boot</title><link>https://bergercookie.dev/post/easy2boot/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Mar 2020 20:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bergercookie.dev/post/easy2boot/</guid><description>Easy2boot is a utility that allows you to flash a USB with multiple bootable images. This gives you the option of always carrying a variety of OSes / tools for all sorts of different scenarios (debugging using a Rescue image / gparted live, install Ubuntu / Windows 10 etc. images)
Here are the contents of a E2B USB stick that I tend to carry with me and use on a regular basis.</description></item><item><title>Scratchpad - LSD - A colorful ls alternative</title><link>https://bergercookie.dev/post/lsd/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Mar 2020 20:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bergercookie.dev/post/lsd/</guid><description>Intro lsd is an alternative to the classic ls UNIX tool. It shows you a listing of files, directories, links, named pipes etc. The difference to its predecessor is that it makes use of Glyph-rich fonts such as Nerd Fonts as well as an abundance of colors preconfigured and available from start.
Troubleshooting &amp;amp; How-to &amp;ldquo;Permission denied&amp;rdquo; when root or $LD_PRELOAD error on a gtk3-related library You&amp;rsquo;ve probably installed lsd via snap.</description></item><item><title>🛠️ Scratchpad - Linux Tooling</title><link>https://bergercookie.dev/post/linux-tooling/</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 Mar 2020 20:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bergercookie.dev/post/linux-tooling/</guid><description>A scratchpad of techniques, tools, and routines that I tend to use on my Linux machines. Most probably not all of these bullets are going to be useful in your case, but I hope that at there will be at least a 10% of them which you won&amp;rsquo;t have come across before or that you&amp;rsquo;ll find useful and add to your arsenal.
P.S. Parts wrapped in [[ ]] are links to articles not added yet.</description></item><item><title>Using Albert to boost your productivity</title><link>https://bergercookie.dev/post/albert-plugins/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2019 15:28:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bergercookie.dev/post/albert-plugins/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve lately been very active developing plugins for the Albert launcher for many parts of my daily routine. For those of you that don&amp;rsquo;t know it, Albert is an application launcher for Linux. It&amp;rsquo;s written in C++ and its GUI is built on top of Qt. The current post is a short summary of the plugins I&amp;rsquo;ve implemented to automate parts of my current routine and maximise my productivity along with advise and, hopefully, useful information on how to do the same for your needs via Albert.</description></item><item><title>🛠️ Scratchpad - CV Applications II Course by OpenCV</title><link>https://bergercookie.dev/post/opencv-applications-ii/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bergercookie.dev/post/opencv-applications-ii/</guid><description>Computer Vision Applications using OpenCV Facial Landmark Detection Improve the speed of Facial Landmark Detection: Use face detection that comes with OS - if possible (e.g., Android, iOS) Skip frames - e.g,. run every 3 frames Downscale image, detect faces there &amp;hellip; then propagate bboxes to original image (dividing the coordinates by the scale used for resizing the original frame.). Then just do landmark detection on original image and computed bounding box Improve landmark stabilisation Weighted Moving Average - Average the landmark point location over a small time window Kalman Filtering Optical Flow Code snippets OpenCV - Rescale an image - keep ratio import cv2 # Load image img = cv2.</description></item><item><title>🛠️ Scratchpad - Machine Learning</title><link>https://bergercookie.dev/post/machine-learning/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bergercookie.dev/post/machine-learning/</guid><description>Definition: The science/art of programming computers so that they can learn from data
Popular ML Algorithms Linear &amp;amp; Polynomial Regression Logistic Regression k-nearest Neighbors Support Vector machines Decision Trees Random Forests Ensemble methods Neural Networks Architectures Feedforward Neural Nets Convolutional Nets Recurrent Nets Long short-term memory (LSTM) nets Autoencoders Multi-Layer Perceptons (MLPs) Famous Papers Machine Learning on handwritten digits - 2006 - &amp;lt;www.cs.toronto.edu/~hinton&amp;gt; The Unreasonable Effectiveness of Data - 2009 Useful links - resources www.</description></item><item><title>🛠️ Scratchpad -ROS1</title><link>https://bergercookie.dev/post/ros-faq/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Oct 2019 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bergercookie.dev/post/ros-faq/</guid><description>A scratchpad for common pitfalls, commands, and shortcuts when using ROS1.
Questions/Answers Set an argument based on the exclusive OR of two other arguments This is a really ugly hack, but it gets the job done. Since we don&amp;rsquo;t care much about the name, we set it so that if the user provides both of them at the same time, they get a descriptive message back.
&amp;lt;!-- arg1 XOR arg2 --&amp;gt; &amp;lt;arg if=&amp;#34;$(eval (arg1 !</description></item><item><title>My daily workflow and tools</title><link>https://bergercookie.dev/post/daily-workflow/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 May 2019 15:28:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bergercookie.dev/post/daily-workflow/</guid><description>As this is my first actual post I thought I&amp;rsquo;d write about something I&amp;rsquo;m a big fun of, tooling. More specifically I want to describe my workflow when working or in general when using my machine.
My general goal is to be productive in my day-to-day routine, and automate everything that can actually be automated so that I can focus on the higher-level tasks I&amp;rsquo;m interested in. I admit that sometimes I&amp;rsquo;m overdoing it and automate a task that I don&amp;rsquo;t actually have to but all in all I think this attitude has helped me considerably so far.</description></item></channel></rss>