<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Scratchpad on Bergercookie's Thoughtstream</title><link>https://bergercookie.dev/categories/scratchpad/</link><description>Recent content in Scratchpad on Bergercookie's Thoughtstream</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://bergercookie.dev/categories/scratchpad/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>🛠️ Scratchpad - CV Applications II Course by OpenCV</title><link>https://bergercookie.dev/post/opencv-applications-ii/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bergercookie.dev/post/opencv-applications-ii/</guid><description>Computer Vision Applications using OpenCV Facial Landmark Detection Improve the speed of Facial Landmark Detection: Use face detection that comes with OS - if possible (e.g., Android, iOS) Skip frames - e.g,. run every 3 frames Downscale image, detect faces there &amp;hellip; then propagate bboxes to original image (dividing the coordinates by the scale used for resizing the original frame.). Then just do landmark detection on original image and computed bounding box Improve landmark stabilisation Weighted Moving Average - Average the landmark point location over a small time window Kalman Filtering Optical Flow Code snippets OpenCV - Rescale an image - keep ratio import cv2 # Load image img = cv2.</description></item><item><title>🛠️ Scratchpad - ROS1</title><link>https://bergercookie.dev/post/ros-faq/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Oct 2019 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bergercookie.dev/post/ros-faq/</guid><description>A scratchpad for common pitfalls, commands, and shortcuts when using ROS1.
Questions/Answers Set an argument based on the exclusive OR of two other arguments This is a really ugly hack, but it gets the job done. Since we don&amp;rsquo;t care much about the name, we set it so that if the user provides both of them at the same time, they get a descriptive message back.
&amp;lt;!-- arg1 XOR arg2 --&amp;gt; &amp;lt;arg if=&amp;#34;$(eval (arg1 !</description></item></channel></rss>