<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>tooling on Bergercookie's Thoughtstream</title><link>https://bergercookie.dev/categories/tooling/</link><description>Recent content in tooling on Bergercookie's Thoughtstream</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://bergercookie.dev/categories/tooling/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>5 Albert Plugins to 5 Workflow Issues</title><link>https://bergercookie.dev/post/5-albert-plugins-to-5-common-problems/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bergercookie.dev/post/5-albert-plugins-to-5-common-problems/</guid><description>This is part two of my articles on the Albert launcher. Read the first part here
This post outlines 5 common issues that I had been facing during my day-to-day development and the solutions that I came up with via 5 Albert plugins respectively.
TL;DR The purpose of these plugins is a) to avoid context-switching and b) have a single tool with a single interface instead X different tools with their own corresponding interfaces.</description></item><item><title>Using Albert to boost your productivity</title><link>https://bergercookie.dev/post/albert-plugins/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2019 15:28:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bergercookie.dev/post/albert-plugins/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve lately been very active developing plugins for the Albert launcher for many parts of my daily routine. For those of you that don&amp;rsquo;t know it, Albert is an application launcher for Linux. It&amp;rsquo;s written in C++ and its GUI is built on top of Qt. The current post is a short summary of the plugins I&amp;rsquo;ve implemented to automate parts of my current routine and maximise my productivity along with advise and, hopefully, useful information on how to do the same for your needs via Albert.</description></item><item><title>My daily workflow and tools</title><link>https://bergercookie.dev/post/daily-workflow/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 May 2019 15:28:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bergercookie.dev/post/daily-workflow/</guid><description>As this is my first actual post I thought I&amp;rsquo;d write about something I&amp;rsquo;m a big fun of, tooling. More specifically I want to describe my workflow when working or in general when using my machine.
My general goal is to be productive in my day-to-day routine, and automate everything that can actually be automated so that I can focus on the higher-level tasks I&amp;rsquo;m interested in. I admit that sometimes I&amp;rsquo;m overdoing it and automate a task that I don&amp;rsquo;t actually have to but all in all I think this attitude has helped me considerably so far.</description></item></channel></rss>